commdiginews.com 2019-11-17

# Privacy Policy - Communities Digital News

Communities Digital News is a Maryland, LLC that is contributor owned. It’s primary purpose is to create content covering Politics, Global Affairs, Sports, Travel, Family, Health, Science, Business and current news.

Communities Digital News LLC (“CDN”, “we” or “us”) recognizes the importance of protecting the information it collects from users in the operation of its Web site, commdiginews.com (“CDN’s Web site”) as well as other activities. As such, CDN takes reasonable steps to maintain the security, integrity and privacy of this information.

**TYPES OF INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

The information we gather falls into two categories: (1) information voluntarily supplied by visitors to the site when they sign up to receive our email newsletters, post comments in any of the public posting areas on our site, respond to user surveys, participate in interactive activities such as polls, or view more information about a story, and the like; and (2) anonymous tracking information that is automatically gathered as visitors navigate through our site and review our email newsletters and other email messages.  This information may be collected directly by us or it may be collected by third-party partners or service providers on our behalf.  Third parties featured on or linked to by our Web site, such as advertisers and others that display promotional messages on our site or offer products and services through our site (“Advertisers”), may be gathering information as well, through processes we don’t control.

**_Information You Voluntarily Supply to Us_**

We may collect and store information that you voluntarily supply to us while on our site.  This may include personally identifying information if you choose to provide it.  In accessing and using CDN’s Web site, you may have the opportunity to voluntarily submit some or all of the following types of information:

  * Contact information, such as your name, telephone number, postal mailing address and email address;
  * Demographic information, such as gender, country (and, where applicable, your postal code);
  * Communications preferences, such as which email messages you would like to receive from us;
  * Information posted in public posting areas and other interactive areas of our site.

You are not required to provide information about yourself to visit our site.  However, if you wish to receive any of our newsletters, you will be required to provide us the email address to which you want us to send the newsletters as well as your name, the country in which you reside, and, where applicable, your postal code.  If you wish to participate in any of the interactive features of our site – for example, by posting comments, voting in a poll, viewing additional information about a story, or viewing premium content, you may be required to register with Disqus.  When you register with Disqus, you’ll be asked for your email address or Web site address.  You’ll also have to provide a username and a password. WithDisqusyou have the choice of registering your account with an email address, or by using your Facebook, Google, Twitter, or Disqus credentials. You may view Disqus’s privacy policy at https://help.disqus.com/terms-and-policies/disqus-privacy-policy.

**_Information That Is Collected Automatically_**

We also may collect and store, and permit our service providers to collect and store, information that does not identify you personally that is generated automatically as you navigate through the site.  For example, we and our service providers may collect limited information about the configuration of your computer or other device through which you visit our site, including the type of browser software you use, the operating system you’re running, the resolution of your computer monitor, the Web site that referred you, the type of mobile device you’re using to access our site (for example, iPad, iPhone, BlackBerry, Android device, tablet, etc.), and your IP address.  (Your IP address is a numerical address that is used by computers connected to the Internet to identify your computer so that data – such as the Web pages you want to view – can be transmitted to you.  We also use IP address information for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes.)  We use this information to make our site as useful as we can for as many users as possible.

**_Cookies and Pixel Tags_**

We may use “cookies,” a standard feature found in browser software, to enhance your experience on the site.  Cookies are small files that your Web browser places on your hard drive for record-keeping purposes.  We also may use pixel tags (sometimes referred to as “clear GIFs” or “Web beacons”) to collect non-personally identifying information about how our visitors use our site.  By showing how and when visitors and registered users use the site, cookies and pixel tags help us deliver more relevant content to users, identify how many unique users visit our site and various pages within our site, and anonymously track user interests, trends and patterns.  For example, we may use these technologies to collect aggregate information about the time visitors spend on each page of our site, the number of visits made to each page or section of our site, and the content that visitors select and copy using the standard copy and paste tool provided in standard Web browsers.  Providers of web analytics services may use cookies and pixel tags to gather this sort of information on our behalf.  And Advertisers that display ads or other promotional messages (“Ads”) on our site (and their providers of ad serving and other advertising services) may use cookies and pixel tags of their own in connection with Ads displayed on our site, as described below under the heading “Data Collected in Connection with Ads.”

Providers of email transmission services use pixel tags to record whether an email is opened and whether you click on any of the links in the email, as described below under the heading “Data Collected in Connection with Emails.”

We also may use cookies to record certain preferences that you enter or set while using the site.  For example, if you are a registered user and you opt to have the site “remember you,” we’ll use cookies to automatically store your log-in information so that you won’t have to re-enter it the next time you visit.

The help function on most Web browsers contains information on how to set your browser to notify you before accepting a cookie or to disable cookies entirely.  However, if you don’t accept cookies, you won’t be able to take advantage of various features on our site that are available to other visitors.

**HOW WE USE COLLECTED INFORMATION**

**_Generally_**

We use the information we collect from you while you are using the site in a variety of ways, including, for example, to provide you with services and communications that you have requested, to send you email updates, newsletters, and other communications which you have elected to receive, to deliver our site content to you, to measure site traffic, to measure user interests and traffic patterns, and to improve the site and the services and features offered via the site.

**_Your Email Address_**

Communities Digital News email list collects email addresses and zip codes; This information will never be used for any purpose other than the distribution of regular email newsletters.  The email list is under the direct control of Communities Digital News and will never be made available to any third party, advertiser, or contributor to Communities Digital News.

Email addresses will never be sold, bartered, or provided to any third party for any reason.

We do not collect information from readers / site visitors who email writers or Communities Digital News (jacquie.kubin@commdiginews.com)

**_Data Collected in Connection with Emails_**

Email newsletters you elect to receive from us are transmitted through Mailchimp from The Rocket Science Group LLC. Mailchimp uses pixel tag technology to determine whether an email has been opened. In addition, when you click on any link in an email newsletter or marketing message you have elected to receive, Mailchimp recognizes that fact. This information is used in the aggregate to measure the rate at which emails are opened and various links are clicked, to measure user interests and traffic patterns, and to improve the content of the email newsletters and the services and features offered through the email newsletter and marketing messages.

Because some of this information is linked to individual email addresses, it is personally identifiable. You can view Mailchimp’s privacy policy at https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/.

**_Data Collected in Connection with Ads_**

Advertisers that display Ads on our site (and other advertising services) may use cookies and pixel tags of their own to record your Web browser’s interaction with a given Ad.  This technique allows the Advertiser (and its providers of ad serving and other advertising services) to track how Ads are displayed, and which are clicked on, and to limit the number of times a given Ad is shown to you.  The use of cookies and pixel tags may also enable these Advertisers (and their providers of ad serving and other advertising services) to serve ads to our users based on their perceived interests as gleaned from their visits to this and other Web sites.  For example, DoubleClick, a provider of ad serving and other advertising services, may set cookies in connection with Ads displayed on our Web site through our relationship with Google.  For a detailed description of Google’s interest-based advertising program, or to opt out of receiving interest-based ads from Google,  ** _click here_**.

These advertiser platforms are guided by their own privacy policies.  Advertisement platforms may change and this policy will be updated to include additions or changes of advertiser platforms.

Of those advertisements, they are delivered from hundreds of Advertisers across a multitude of Digital Content Provider properties. When you visit one of these properties, our automated system may collect “click stream data” related to your visit to the property.

Please contact [Jacquie.kubin@communitiesdigitalnews.com](mailto:Jacquie.kubin@communitiesdigitalnews.com) if any advertising is seen as questionable or offensive.  Please note the advertisers name, and if possible, link the ad goes to.

> _Click Stream Data is a virtual trail that a user leaves behind while  [surfing](http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/S/surf.html) the Internet. A clickstream is a record of a user’s activity on the Internet, including every Web site and every page of every Web site that the user visits, how long the user was on a page or site, in what order the pages were visited, any [newsgroups](http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/N/newsgroup.html) that the user participates in and even the e-mail addresses of mail that the user sends and receives. Both [ISPs](http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/I/ISP.html) and individual Web sites are capable of tracking a user’s clickstream. (definition provided by http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/C/clickstream.html)_

Click stream data is anonymous and can include information such as your IP address, content or pages viewed, the date and time at which that content was viewed and any interaction with content and advertisements on those properties. Technologies used to collect this click stream data include cookies and Web beacons.

In order to improve performance, we augment our click stream data with non-personally-identifiable behavioral and demographic data from Digital Content Providers and other partners. This anonymous data may include such things as postal code, age and gender. It may also include GPS location provided by Digital Content Providers with mobile properties.

Communities Digital News complies with and supports the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)

Communities Digital News utilizes [Disqus](https://www.disqus.com/ "disqus.com") to manage comments.  Disqus is governed by their company user and privacy policies.

Communities Digital News will endeavor to adhere and follows generally accepted industry standards for acceptable content and to protect against unauthorized access to, destruction or disclosure of data.  Any data that may be stored on our servers is treated as confidential and is not made generally available to the public or any third party.

Contributors are edited and we will not publish content that violates Communities Digital News content guidelines. Some examples include content that:

Adult Content  
Content that is abusive or harmful to any group including women and children  
Violent or advocating racial intolerance.  
Copyrighted material without direct and clear attribution to original source  
Abuse of Drug, alcohol, and tobacco-related content  
How to Hacking and cracking content  
Content that promotes Violence  
Content that promotes inappropriate use of violence and/or weapons  
Content that would be generally considered to be illegal

Communities Digital News does report on the news and policy as it affects the conversation.  However when discussing sensitive issues, including gun ownership and law, LGBT issues, Immigration, or other issues, we demand that those discussions are respectful.

Our servers are protected by firewalls and are located in secure data facilities to further increase security. Please keep in mind, however, that despite these reasonable efforts to protect data on our servers no method of transmission over the Internet is guaranteed to be secure.

Therefore, while we strive to protect your personal data at all times, we cannot guarantee its absolute security and shall not be liable for any breach of security by an outside party.

Communities Digital News, LLC  
A Maryland Limited Liability Corporation  
Contact: Jacquie Kubin – [Jacquie.kubin@commdiginews.com  
](mailto:Jacquie.kubin@commdiginews.com)301-503-4533

**GDPR COMPLIANCE**

The General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”), which takes effect on May 25, 2018, is a new version of the existing data protection laws defined and enforced by the European Union. The GDPR imposes new rules regarding the processing of personal data of data subjects’ located in the EU. CDN is fully committed to comply with GDPR prior to its effective date.

We may engage secure third-party companies to store or process your personal data in the United States or in other countries. If you are a resident of the European Economic Area ( **“EEA”** ) we will take appropriate measures to ensure that your personal data receives an adequate level of data protection upon its transfer outside of the EEA. If you are a resident of a jurisdiction where transfer of your personal data requires your consent, then your consent to this Privacy Policy includes your express consent for such transfer of your data.

If at any point you wish to access your personal information to (1) change your preferences, (2) review the accuracy, (3) correct, supplement or modify your information, you may either send an e-mail to jacquie.kubin@commdiginews.com, or a written request to:

**Communities Digital News LLC, Attn: Privacy Policy/ Data Protection Officer, PO Box 763, Rockville MD, 20852**

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

The Web is an evolving medium.  If we need to change this Privacy Policy in the future, we will post the revised Privacy Policy on our site and update the “Effective Date,” above, to reflect the date of the changes.  By continuing to use this Web site after we post such changes, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, as modified.
